number one asks a reaction with a
negative value for the change in free
energy is referred to as exothermic
endothermic exergonic endergonic so what
are we talking about we're talking about
free energy so Gibbs free energy is
associated with Delta G and we're
looking for a negative value for this
change exothermic and endothermic these
relate to enp exothermic means Delta H
is negative and endothermic means Delta
H is positive so those are not the ones
that we're looking for exergonic and
endergonic are words that relate instead
to Delta G to Gibs free energy a
negative Delta G is referred to as an
exergonic reaction endergonic would be
Delta G is positive a negative value for
the change in Gibbs free energy that's
Delta g equals negative that is going to
be exonic